<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<resources>

    <string name="app_name">YogaTutorial</string>
    <string name="action_settings">Settings</string>
    <string name="hello_world">Hello world!</string>
    <string name="exploreasana">Explore Asanas</string>
    <string name="disease">Disease</string>
    <string name="aboutyoga">About Yoga</string>
    <string name="aboutyoga1">"\n"<b>Introduction</b>"\n"
        Yoga is from the Sanskrit word Yug meaning union {with the Divine}."\n"  
There are various types of yoga. Before we examine the differences, we should remember that all of 
them lead to the same goal, "\n"unification with the Divine."\n"
The yoga paths can be broadly classified into "\n"
Bhakti Yoga: Path of Devotion"\n"
Karma Yoga: Path of Selfless Action"\n"
Jnana Yoga : Path of Transcendental Knowledge"\n"
Asthanga Yoga: Path of Patanjali (eight-step path)"\n"  
Unfortunately, yoga in the west has come to mean hatha yoga "\n"
which is mainly physical exercise and postures (asanas)."\n"
In fact, asanas is only a single step in the eight-step path (Asthanga yoga of patanjali)"\n".
Patanjali is quick to point out that asanas are to be used as a stepping stone for the higher paths,"\n"
since just working on the beauty and welfare of an impermanent object (the body) is a waste of time and effort."\n" 
Asthanga yoga is sometimes referred to as Raja yoga ."\n" 
However, Asthanga yoga is more of a philosophy like basic research while raja yoga usually refers to specific techniques"\n" 
which are based on not only Asthanga yoga but also on various [minor] upanishhads."\n"

"\n" <b>Top 10 yoga benefits</b>"\n" 
"\n" <b>1.</b> All-round fitness. You are truly healthy when you are not just physically fit but also mentally and emotionally balanced."\n" 
As Sri Sri Ravi Shankar puts it “Health is not a mere absence of disease. It is a dynamic expression of life – "\n" 
in terms of how joyful, loving and enthusiastic you are.” This is where yoga helps: postures, pranayama and meditation are a holistic fitness package."\n"    
"\n" <b>2.</b> Weight loss. Sun Salutations and Kapal Bhati pranayama are some ways to help lose weight with yoga."\n" 
Moreover, with regular practice of yoga, we tend to become more sensitive to the kind of food our body asks for and when."\n" 
This can also help keep a check on weight."\n" 
"\n" <b>3.</b> Stress relief. A few minutes of yoga during the day can be a great way to get rid of"\n"  
stress that accumulates daily - in both the body and mind."\n"  
Yoga postures, pranayama and meditation are effective techniques to release stress."\n"  
"\n"<b> 4.</b> Inner peace. We all love to visit peaceful, serene spots, rich in natural beauty."\n" 
Yoga is also one of the best ways to calm a disturbed mind."\n" 
"\n" <b>5.</b> Improved immunity. Our system is a seamless blend of the body, mind and spirit."\n" 
An irregularity in the body affects the mind and similarly unpleasantness or restlessness"\n"  
in the mind can manifest as an ailment in the body. Yoga poses massage organs and stregthen muscles;"\n" 
breathing techniques and meditation release stress and improve immunity."\n" 
"\n" <b>6.</b> Living with greater awareness. The mind is constantly involved in activity – swinging from the past to the future –"\n" 
 but never staying in the present.By simply being aware of this tendency of the mind, we can actually save ourselves from getting stressed or worked up and relax the mind."\n" 
  Yoga and pranayama help create that awareness and bring the mind back to the present moment, where it can stay happy and focused."\n" 
"\n" <b>7.</b> Better relationships. Yoga can even help improve your relationship with your spouse, parents, friends or loved ones!"\n" 
 A mind that is relaxed, happy and contented is better able to deal with sensitive relationship matters."\n" 
  Yoga and meditation work on keeping the mind happy and peaceful; benefit from the strengthened special bond you share with people close to you."\n" 
"\n" <b>8.</b> Increased energy. Shuttling between multiple tasks through the day can sometimes be quite exhausting."\n" 
 A few minutes of yoga everyday provides the secret to feeling fresh and energetic even after a long day."\n" 
 A 10-minute online guided meditation benefits you immensely, leaving you refreshed and recharged in the middle of a hectic day."\n"  
"\n" <b>9.</b> Better flexibility and posture.Regular yoga practice stretches and tones the body muscles and also makes them strong."\n" 
It also helps improve your body posture when you stand, sit, sleep or walk."\n"  
"\n" <b>10.</b> Better intuition. Yoga and meditation have the power to improve your intuitive ability so that you "\n" 
effortlessly realize what needs to be done, when and how, to yield positive results. It works."\n"  
You only need to experience it yourself."\n" 
   </string>
    <string name="menu">Menu</string>
    <string name="text">Text</string>
    <string name="video">video</string>
    <string name="siddhasana">Siddhasana</string>
    <string name="bhujangasana">Bhujangasana</string>
    <string name="list">List Of Asanas</string>
    <string name="dlist">List Of Diseases</string>
    <string name="asthma_asanalist">List Of Asanas For Curing Asthma</string>
    <string name="bp_asanalist">List Of Asanas For Curing bp</string>
    <string name="cancer_asanalist">List Of Asanas For Curing cancer</string>
    <string name="cervical_asanalist">List Of Asanas For Curing cervical</string>
    <string name="diabetes_asanalist">List Of Asanas For Curing diabetes</string>
    <string name="hernia_asanalist">List Of Asanas For Curing hernia</string>
    <string name="obesity_asanalist">List Of Asanas For Curing obesity</string>
    <string name="asana1">SIDDHASANA</string>
    <string name="string1">"\n" <b>Introduction</b>"\n"
        "It is said many saints acquired super natural powers by sitting in this asana. Perhaps on account of this the name has been given as such. 
        “Siddhi” means super natural power. Stout persons find this asana easy."\n
        
<b>"Procedure"</b>
"<b>1.</b>Spread a blanket four folded."
"<b>2.</b>Sit over it in the usual way."
"<b>3.</b>Place the heel of one leg just below the anus."
"<b>4.</b>Place the heel of the other leg below the generative organs."
"<b>5.</b>In this pose the joints of the two heels will be just touching each other."
"<b>6.</b>By a continued practice for a fortnight or so it will be easy."
"<b>7.</b>The hands may be placed in chin mindra style."
"Then come to the original position."\n

"<b>Fruit of Asana</b>"
"One can conveniently sit in this pose for longer time. This asana will help to keep up brahmacharya."
" Because sitting is erect the internal organs are not pressed and they are kept in their natural positions."\n
"<b>Caution</b>" 
"Ladies need not do this Asana. There is a another variety under this with some slight modification.
The hands are joined as we do “Namaskar” (a form of welcome)." 
"This pose is taken to seek boons and blessings." 
"This is known asthamasana as described in writing." 
        
       </string>
   <string name="asana2">SARVANGASANA</string>
   <string name="string2"> "\n" <b>Introduction</b>"\n"
"The word “Sarvaanga” means all portions of the body. 
Hence this asana is the one to give an all round benefit."\n 
"Any body can do this, quite comfortably for a minimum of ten minutes. "\n
<b>"Procedure"</b>
"<b>1.</b> Spread a blanket length wise."
"<b>2.</b> Lie down on the blanket length wise."
"<b>3.</b> Raise both legs evenly."
"<b>4.</b>Place the palms on the sides so that the legs can be raised further and support them."
"<b>5.</b> Raise the body till the chest touches the chin. 
If it is correctly done the body will give about 80 degrees angle to the head."
"<b>6.</b> Then slowly come to the original position. This is nothing new pose."
 "Some people while standing place the palms on the hip portion to give a majestic look." 
 "In the same way it is done with the head down on the ground."\n
"<b>Fruit of Asana</b>"
"The back bone gets good quantity of blood circulation. 
Further the back bone will become more flexible."
"Youth and the flexibility of the back bone are proportional."
"This asana will help to keep up Brahmacharya. Digestion power is increased. 
Kidneys will function normally."\n
  "<b>Caution:</b> In the creation there is difference in the body structure between male and female." 
"Young ladies before marriage can do this asana, when the uterus is under developing stage."
"But pregnant ladies should not do this asana."\n
 "So also during monthly period ladies need not do this asana. "
 "Normally in our country young girls get maturity between 14-15 age." 
 "They also grow up after maturity."\n 
 "Hence when this asana is practiced at this period all the internal organs will become strong."

</string>
   
     <string name="asana3">MANDUKASANA</string>
     <string name="string3">"\n" <b>Introduction</b>"\n"
        "The shape of this formation resembles a frog, so that’s why this asana is called Mandukasana."\n 
        "In sanskrit frog is called a manduk."\n
"<b>Procedure</b>"
"<b>1.</b>Sit in Vajrasana with both the legs bent in the rear."
   "<b>2.</b>Keep both the paws of the legs touching each other. Keep both the heels opened out." 
   "Sit with waist and back straight supporting the buttocks on the two heels."
    "<b>3.</b>Now separate the knees as far apart as possible. This is Manduk sitting."
    "<b>4.</b>Now for Mandukasana bring both the knees in the front touching each other."
    "<b>5.</b>Close both the fists of the hands and keep them on the belly on both the sides of the navel."
  " <b>6.</b> Lower the body in front and let the forehead touch the ground."
"<b>7.</b>Come back in first position and relax."\n
"<b>Fruit of Asana</b>"
 "Mandukasana improves functions of all organs. It is advised in the treatment of constipation, diabetes and digestive disorders."
    "This asana is effective in reducing the weight of thighs,hips and the abdomen."
    "This asana strengthens the lower parts of the loins."
    "This asana stimulates the digestive system."
    "It benefits which Padmasana gives can be obtained from this asana also."\n
"<b>Caution</b>"
"Not for the people who are suffering from peptic or duodenal ulcer, severe back pain and cardiac problem," 
and patients who have undergone abdominal surgery."
        
   </string>
    <string name="asana4">BADDHA PADMASANA</string>
    <string name="string4"> "\n" <b>Introduction</b>"\n"
        "This is another sub type under Padhmasana."\n
"There is an opinion that this is superior even to Padhmasana."\n
"<b>Procedure</b>"
"<b>1.</b>Spread a blanket."
"<b>2.</b>Sit over it in the usual way."
"<b>3.</b>Place the legs as in Padhmasana."
"<b>4.</b>Take the right hand towards back and catch hold of the right toe."
"<b>5.</b>Take the left hand towards the back and catch hold of the left toe." 
"Though this is easily said, it is not quite easy to do." 
"If it is not possible to catch the toe try to take the hand as for back as possible." 
"<b>6.</b>Then come to the original position."\n
"<b>Fruit of Asana</b>" 
"This will cure unnecessary big belly. Hunch back will go away. This is more or less a 
tapas pose." 
</string>
    
    <string name="asana5">BHUJANGASANA</string>
   <string name="string5"><b>Introduction</b>"\n"
       "In the previous asana the near portion of the back bone was given a bend."
   " By this asana the upper portion of the back bone is given a bend."
    "The correct position of this asana will look like a serpent raising its head."\n
"<b>Procedure</b>"
"<b>1.</b>Place a blanket folded length wise. "
"<b>2.</b>Lie down on the blanket gently facing the ground." 
"<b>3.</b>Give a relaxed condition of the body."
"<b>4.</b>Place the hands on the sides, palm facing the ground." 
"<b>5.</b>Raise the head and chest."
"<b>6.</b>It will be noticed that the back bone is given a backward curve at the beginning portion." 
"<b>7.</b>Gently come to the original position."
"Do like this some six or seven times." 
"In the previous position the legs and the head was raised but in this only the head is raised."\n
"<b>Fruit of Asana</b>"
"All forms of diseases of the generative organs will be cured."
"Hunch back will be cured. This will keep the Kundalini sakthi to raise up."
"Since the intestines are pressed the undigested food is moved towards anus. "
"For young girls this asana is good. In the growing period the eturus will become strong."
 "Pregnant ladies should not do this Asana."
 </string>

   
    <string name="asana6">CHAKRASANA</string>
   <string name="string6">"\n" <b>Introduction</b>"\n"
"Chakrasana is the most important and fundamental backbend."\n
 "In this pose, you have to lie on your back and push up, balancing just on the hands and feet."\n 
 "This pose is called a bridge."\n
 " A back limber is a skill in which the pose is achieved by bending backward from a standing position."\n 
<b>Procedure</b>
<b>1.</b>Lie facing upward on the floor."\n"
<b>2.</b>Bend your knees and set your feet on the floor,"\n"
heels as close to the sitting bones as possible."\n"
<b>3.</b>Bend your elbows and spread your palms on the floor beside your head."\n"
 Forearms relatively perpendicular to the floor, fingertips pointing towards shoulders."\n"
<b>4.</b>While inhaling, slowly begin to raise the head, back and buttocks off the floor while arcing the spine."\n"
<b>5.</b>Hold for the duration of the held inhaled breath."\n" 
<b>6.</b>When you can’t hold the breath comfortable any longer, slowly exhale and return the back to the floor."\n"
<b>7.</b>Slide the legs out straight returning to the shavasan."\n"
<b>Fruit Of Asana</b>"\n"
<b>1.</b>Strengthens the arms, wrists, buttocks, abdomen and spine."\n"
<b>2.</b>Stretches the lungs and chest."\n"
<b>3.</b>Stimulates the thyroid and pituitary."\n"
<b>4.</b>Increases energy and counteracts depression."\n"
<b>5.</b>Therapeutic for asthma, back pain, infertility and osteoporosis."\n"

<b>Caution</b> "\n"
Not for the persons, who have back injury, carpel tunnel and syndrome,"\n" 
diarrhoea, headache, heart problems, high or low blood pressure."\n"
 </string>   
    <string name="asana7">DHANURASANA</string>
     <string name="string7">"\n" <b>Introduction</b>"\n"
         "The word “Dhanur” means a bow. 
        "If this asana is done correctly it will look like a bow. 
        "In this connection a clarification from Astrology seems relevant. 
        "For the sign Dhanur (Sagittarius), the Lord is Guru (Brahaspati). 
        "This house or Rasi, (as technically known) is considered a special beneficial sign. 
        "Further in Gita we find Lord Krishna’s words as, “Among the twelve months I am the month of Dhanur.” 
        "(This period is between the middle of December to the middle of January). 
        "So much greatness goes with this name. Hence this asana is great induced.

"<b>Procedure</b>"
"<b>1.</b>Spread a blanket folded length wise."\n 
"<b>2.</b>Lie down on it facing the ground. "\n
"<b>3.</b>Place both hands on sides as usual."\n 
"<b>4.</b>Slowly bend the legs evenly without bearing space between the knee caps. "\n
"<b>5.</b>Catch hold of the toes with the fingers raising the head also."\n 
"<b>6.</b>It will be seen that by this the backbone is given a fine curve"\n 
"Stout persons may find it difficult. For them leaving a space between the knee will enable them to catch the toes."\n
 "By continuous practice the space will be minimized."\n

"<b>Fruit of Asana</b>"\n
"This asana gives many benefits."\n 
"Indigestion, hunch back, Rheumatism, Pain in elbow joints and Palm joints will be cured."\n 
"Gastro intestinal troubles will also be cured. There is still a difficult pose, as catching hold of alternate toes."\n
         
    </string>
     <string name="asana8">GARUDASANA</string>
     <string name="string8">"\n" <b>Introduction</b>"\n"
         "For Garudasana you need strength, flexibility, and endurance,"\n 
     "but also unwavering concentration that actually calms the fluctuations (vrtti) of consciousness."\n 
      "This is true of all the yoga poses, but it's a bit more obvious in pretzel-like Eagle."\n  
"<b>Procedure</b>"\n 
"<b>1.</b>Start from Utkatasana and shift your weight onto the right leg."\n  
"<b>2.</b>Bring the left leg up and cross the left thigh over the right."\n  
"<b>3.</b>Hook the left foot around the right calf."\n  
"<b>4.</b>Bring the arms out in front."\n  
"<b>5.</b>Cross the right arm over the left and bring the palms to touch."\n  
"<b>6.</b>Lift the elbows while keeping the shoulders sliding down the back."\n  
"<b>7.</b>Hold the position for some time and repeat."\n 
"<b>8.</b>Stay for 15 to 30 seconds, then unwind the legs and arms and stand in Tadasana again."\n  
"<b>9.</b>Repeat for the same length of time with the arms and legs reversed."\n 

"<b>Fruit of Asana</b>"\n 
"Strengthens and stretches the ankles and calves."\n  
"Stretches the thighs, hips, shoulders, and upper back."\n  
 "Improves concentration."\n  
"Improves sense of balance."\n 

"<b>Caution</b>"\n  
"The persons with knee injuries should avoid this pose."\n
</string> 
     
  <string name="asana9">GOMUKHASANA</string>
  <string name="string9">"\n" <b>Introduction</b>"\n"
      This asana resembles the face of the cow that is why"\n"
   it is called the cow face or gomukhasana."\n"
<b>Procedure</b>"\n"
<b>1.</b>From Knee to Ankle, slide the knees to center stacking the right knee"\n"
 directly over the left."\n"
<b>2.</b>It may be helpful to come forward onto the hands and knees to align the knees."\n"
<b>3.</b>Then separate the feet and come back to sit between the feet."\n" 
<b>4.</b>Bring the left arm up towards the ceiling."\n" 
<b>5.</b>Bend the left elbow, bringing the left hand down the center of the back."\n"
<b>6.</b>Bring the right arm out to the right side, bend the elbow and "\n"
bring the right arm up the center of the back."\n" 
<b>7.</b>Hold hands behind the back."\n" 
<b>8.</b>Draw both elbows toward the center."\n" 
<b>9.</b>Hold the position for four to eight breaths and then come back to the relaxed posture."\n"

<b>Fruit of Asana</b>"\n"
It stretches the ankles, hips and thighs, shoulders, armpits and triceps, and chest."\n" 

<b>Caution</b>"\n"
"\n" 
Not for the persons who have serious neck, shoulder or knee problems."\n"
 </string>   
    <string name="asana10">HALASANA</string>
    <string name="string10">"\n" <b>Introduction</b>"\n"
        "This asana gives a backward bend to the back bone."\n 
    "As the name goes, the pose looks like a plough. "\n
"<b>Procedure</b>"
"<b>1.</b>Spread a soft blanket."
"<b>2.</b>Lie down on it in the usual way."
"<b>3.</b>Place both hands on the sides in the usual way, palms facing the ground."
"<b>4.</b>Raise both the legs evenly without bending when the legs are raised the hands should not be taken from the ground."
"<b>5.</b>Making a curve of the spine bring the toes towards the ground away from the head."
"<b>6.</b>Bring the legs further so that the toes touch the ground."
"<b>7.</b>Breathe slowly during asana."
"<b>8.</b>Then come to the original position."
"This asana can be practiced in three stages." 
"At the first stage raise the legs half way. 
"Then in the second stage give a bend to the spine so that the toes are nearer to the ground."
 "In the third stage touch the ground with the toes. "
"There is another variety which is rather difficult. "
"As in Pachamothasana hold the toes with the fingers."\n
"<b>Fruit of Asana</b>"
"The spinal region get much benefit. This asana removes lethargy."
"Chronic constipation is removed. Wind trouble in stomach will go away."
"Liver trouble will be cured."\n  
"<b>Caution</b>"
"Due to physical shape, some may not be able to take the legs, towards back position.
"Such persons can adopt this easy way. After lying down raise both the "
"legs to the possible extent giving a gap of two feet or so from the ground."
"Then bring the legs to the original position. Repeat this same six or eight times."
"This form of practice will enable to bring the legs towards back."
</string>

  <string name="asana11">SHAVASANA</string>
   <string name="string11">"\n" <b>Introduction</b>"\n"
       "We can truly get in touch with the deepest of Anahata Chakra through Shavasana."\n 
 "In this asana, as we release the whole of the body into the ground and allow the full effect of gravity "\n 
 "to flow through us then we restrain and retain Vayu Tattva."\n  

"<b>Procedure</b>"
"<b>1.</b>Lie down quietly on your back like a corpse. "
"<b>2.</b>Rest your arms at your sides and your palms facing up."  
"<b>3.</b>Clear your mind of thoughts."  
"<b>4.</b>Take long deep breaths and be in a perfectly relaxed condition" 
"<b>5.</b>Stay in the pose for ten minutes and then release the pose."\n 
"<b>Fruit of Asana</b>"  
"This asana relaxes the body, calms the brain and helps relieve stress and mild depression." 
"It also reduces headache, fatigue, and insomnia. Helps to lower blood pressure."\n 
"<b>Caution</b>"
"Back injury or discomfort: Do this pose with your knees bent and your feet on the floor,"  
"hip-distance apart; either bind the thighs parallel to each other with a strap or support" 
"the bent knees on a bolster."  
"In the case of pregnancy: Raise your head and chest on a bolster."
       
   </string> 
    <string name="asana12">KUKKUTASANA</string>
    <string name="string12">"\n" <b>Introduction</b>"\n"
         "This is another sub type of Padhmasana."\n  

"<b>Procedure</b>"
"<b>1.</b>Spread a blanket length wise."  
"<b>2.</b>Sit over it in the usual way." 
"<b>3.</b>Place the legs as in Padhmasana."  
"<b>4.</b>Place the hands in between the leg and the thigh, palm facing the ground." 
"<b>5.</b>On the strength of the hands gently raise the body." 
"<b>6.</b>Then come to the original position."\n

"<b>Fruit of Asana</b>"
"This will cure stomach problems and body pains"
</string>
         

    
 <string name="asana13">MAKARASANA</string>
 <string name="string13">"\n" <b>Introduction</b>"\n"
     Makara means Crocodile."\n" 
 While doing this Asana body resembles the shape of crocodile,"\n"
 hence it is known as Makarasana."\n" 
"\n" <b>Procedure</b>"\n"
<b>1.</b>Lie on your belly, with the arms crossed under your head."\n" 
Turn your head to one side and rest your head on your arms."\n" 
<b>2.</b>Close the eyes and let your whole body relax into the floor."\n"
<b>3.</b>Breathe deeply, pressing the belly down into the floor with each inhalation and hold for 6-10 breaths."\n"
 With each exhalation allow your body to relax deeper into the floor."\n"
<b>4.</b>Bring the palms under your shoulders and slowly press up into child pose or roll over onto your back."\n"

"\n" <b>Fruit of Asana</b> "\n"
<b>1.</b>As all the muscles are relaxed, as well as the heart beats and"\n" 
the breathing also slow down."\n" 
<b>2.</b>Though the basic operation turns slow, the body gets good rest."\n"
<b>3.</b>This is beneficial in Asthma."\n"
<b>4.</b>It corrects the acquired wrong process of respiration due to Asthma etc."\n" 
<b>5.</b>Abdominal muscles get massaged."\n"

"\n" <b>Caution</b>"\n"
<b>1.</b>Those having heart problem, obesity, gas or high blood pressure should not practice."\n"
<b>2.</b>Reduces stress and tension, promotes sleep, regulates blood pressure and reduces anxiety."\n" 

 </string>
    <string name="asana14">MATSYASANA</string>
    <string name="string14">"\n" <b>Introduction</b>"\n"
        "When the back bone has been bent in the forward direction in one asana,"\n 
    "the next should be to bend the back bone in the backward direction."\n 
    "Hence after Sarvangasana this asana has to be done."\n 
   " As the name describes this asana is likely to be in the form of a fish."\n 

"<b>Procedure</b>" 
"<b>1.</b>Spread a blanket folded length-wise."
"<b>2.</b>Sit on it in the usual manner." 
"<b>3.</b>Have the legs in the Padhmasana pose." 
"<b>4.</b>Gently lie down."
"<b>5.</b>Place the hands under the head palms facing the head."
"<b>6.</b>Then bend the back bone and also the head. "
"In bending the neck great care has to be taken so that the neck may not develop sprain."
 "I have found a nice way to understand the angle to which the neck is bent."
  "When we are lying down we see the portion of the roof."
  "If the neck is bent backward our vision falls on the pictures or clock on the wall." 
  "If it is still bent our vision falls on table or something below the clock etc." 
  "If this process is suitable to you, you can also adopt this. "
"<b>7.</b> Then slowly come to the original position.This asana can be practiced in another way also."
Padhmasana position can be had after lying down."\n

"<b>Fruit of Asana</b>"
"This asana is a cure for many diseases."
"This increases the digestion power to a great extent chest troubles, Asthma, etc. are cured." 
"Since the throat and bronchial portions are broadened more fresh air is intaken." 
"The glands in the neck portion are nourished."
"<b>Caution:</b>"\n
" Instead of placing the hands below the head some practise this asana in another way."
 "The toes (of Padhmasana pose) are held by the fingers."
  "If this is suitable method it can be practiced this way also."
  </string> 
    
    <string name="asana15">MAYURASANA</string> 
   <string name="string15">"\n" <b>Introduction</b>"\n"
       "The word “Mayura” means peacock."\n 
   "Since this asana looks like a peacock the name is Mayurasana."\n 
   "The ancient Rishis have observed, nature, animals,"\n
   "birds and creatures living in water so closely that their pose if practiced for man will give special benefits."\n 
   "The bats rest with head down. Monkeys catching hold of a twig hang down raising the head."\n
    "Thus many asanas have some sort of similarity with the poses of several creatures."\n

"<b>Procedure</b>"
"This also comes under the category of difficult asana."
"<b>1.</b>Spread a soft blanket."
"<b>2.</b>Place a cushon or a pillow on one end of the blanket." 
"<b>3.</b>Lie down on the blanket, the cushon being near to the head."
"<b>4.</b>In this position the toes will be on the ground."
"<b>5.</b>Bend the hands at elbow and place the palmes facing the ground." 
"<b>6.</b>Bring the elbows near the naval region." 
"<b>7.</b>Gently raise both legs from the ground." 
"<b>8.</b>Raise the head also." 
"<b>9.</b>The whole weight of the body is on the elbows. Since the naval region is "
"almost the central point for the body there will be equal distance on the two sides."
"<b>10.</b>However, if you happen to fall down there is cushon so that the nose may not be hurt." 
"<b>11.</b>Avoid spectacles during Asana. "
"<b>12.</b>If it is not possible to raise both the legs begin with the raising of one leg at the initial stage." 
"<b>13.</b>Come to the original position slowly." 
"<b>14.</b>A period of ten or twenty seconds is enough for normal person in the early stage."\n
"<b>Fruit of Asana</b>"
"In a few seconds the entire body gets freshness." 
"Indigestion will be removed. All kinds of liver troubles will be cured."
 "This enables the Kundalini Sakthi to raise."\n
"<b>Caution:</b>"
" There is a sub type in this asana which is described as Lolasana."
 "This is easier than Mayurasana. According to my physical frame this is my favourite asana."
  "The procedure is rather simple also. Sit on Padhmasana and lie down. "
  "As in Mayurasana, place the elbows on the naval region."
  "Raise the head and the legs in Padhmasana."
  "Here the chance of falling down is not likely but cushon may be placed to protect the nose."
   "The benefits of Mayurasana are got fully by this also"
   </string>
   
     <string name="asana16">PASCHIMOTHNASANA</string>
    <string name="string16">"\n" <b>Introduction</b>"\n"
        "In the previous asana the back bone was given a backward twist."\n
     "In this asana it is given a forward twist. This a difficult asana for stout persons with big belly."\n 
     "There is a proverb. “Rome was built in a day”."\n 
    " Hence patience and continued practice is essential to get perfection in this asana."\n 
     "Some lean persons can learn in a fortnight training,"\n 
     "while some others may take even a month period."\n

"<b>Procedure</b>"\n
"<b>1.</b>Spread a soft blanket."\n 
"<b>2.</b>Sit on it in the usual way."\n 
"<b>3.</b>Stretch both the legs forward without bending."\n 
"<b>4.</b>Bend the body in the forward direction taking the hands towards the toes."\n 
"<b>5.</b>Catch hold of the toes with the fingers."\n
"Though this is easily said it is very difficult to do."\n 
"In the early stages in bringing the hands towards the toes there will be a wide gap."\n 
"It may not be possible to catch the toes. "\n
"In this case, the legs can be slightly bent to enable to catch the toes."\n 
"Then gradually the legs can be in a straight position."\n

"<b>6.</b>Come to the original position slowly."\n 
"<b>7.</b>Breathe slowly during Asana time."\n 
"<b>8.</b>It is enough that, a few seconds, period in this asana be practiced."\n

"<b>Fruit of Asana</b>"\n
"Several wonderful results are got. Persons having big belly will develop a trim figure in due course."\n 
"Liver, spleen will function normally."\n 
"Piles is also cured. Diabetes can be cured in due course."\n 
"One great personality has described that Sirasasana, Sarvangasana and Pachimothasana"\n
 are the three great boons given to us by the ancient Rishes."\n

</string>


<string name="asana17">SIRSASANA</string>
<string name="string17">"\n" <b>Introduction</b>"\n"
    This pose is the most recognized yoga pose than the other poses."\n"
 Standing on one’s head is called Sirsasana. It is also called the king of the asanas,"\n" 
 so one can practice this asana after having mastery in other asanas."\n" 
"\n" <b>Procedure</b>"\n"
<b>1.</b>Firstly kneel down on the mat. Then interlock the fingers of your hands and"\n"
 place them and your forearms on the extra padding on the yoga mat."\n" 
<b>2.</b>Keep your elbows close together. Place the back of your head into the hollow of the palms."\n"
<b>3.</b>Now, rise up off your knees and take a step or two towards the head."\n"
<b>4.</b>Inhale, and slowly raise the legs until they are vertical."\n"
<b>5.</b>Now, keep your back straight and try to relax and breathe deeply and slowly from the abdomen."\n"
<b>6.</b>Now, concentrate on the brain or the pineal gland between the eyebrows."\n"
<b>7.</b>To release or to come down, bend your knees and lower one leg and then the other."\n"
<b>8.</b>For the beginners, just ask your friend to hold one of your legs while you lower the other leg."\n"

"\n" <b>Fruit of Asana</b>"\n"
<b>1.</b>It promotes hair growth by increasing blood circulation in the scalp."\n"
<b>2.</b>The Shirshasana or the headstand increases the circulation to the brain,"\n"
due to which we can have improved brain functions and increased vitality and confidence."\n"
<b>3.</b>Poor blood circulation, fear, sleeplessness, headache, tension,"\n" 
constipation and the problems of eyes and nose can be improved by it."\n"
<b>4.</b>It also helps to put the spine into correct alignment."\n" 

"\n"<b> Caution</b>"\n"
<b>1.</b>Not for the persons who have high or low blood pressure, atherosclerosis (blocked blood vessels),"\n" 
any history of strokes, serious eye disease, pus in ears, suffering from constipation, suffering from neck injury,"\n"
or also who have organically defective pituitary."\n" 
<b>2.</b>But after recovering from these diseases you can try do this asana."\n"
</string> 
    
    
    <string name="asana18">SHALABHASANA</string>
    <string name="string18">

<b>Procedure</b>"\n" 
<b>1.</b>Lie on your stomach with legs stretched, and feet together, chin resting on the ground."\n" 
Keep both your hands under the thighs."\n" 
<b>2.</b>While inhaling, slowly lift both your legs upwards and stretch as far as possible without bending the knees and toes."\n" 
 Retain this position for some time and then, while exhaling, lower your legs slowly and bring back to the original position."\n" 
<b>3.</b>Repeat this three to four times."\n"  

"\n"<b> Fruit of Asana:</b>"\n" 
However, persons suffering from hernia, cardiac complaints and ulcer should avoid this asana."\n"  
This asana helps to relieve arthritis and rheumatism. "\n" 
It strengthens the whole body, particularly the lungs, abdominal organs, sciatic nerves, prostate glands and the kidneys."\n" 
It also provides relief in cases of diabetes, constipation, dyspepsia, bronchitis, etc."\n" 
</string>
    
    
 <string name="asana19">TADASANA</string>
 <string name="string19">"\n" <b>Introduction</b>"\n"
     Tadasana can be practiced as a starting position for standing poses,"\n"
 in between standing poses, or by itself to improve posture."\n"
 Tadasana is a position used at the beginning and in the middle and in the end,"\n" 
 in which you pay attention to your position, your concentration and your breathing."\n" 
 During intensive Yoga sessions Tadasana makes it easier for you to maintain your meditative focus."\n"

"\n" <b>Procedure</b>"\n"
<b>1.</b>Stand erect, legs together, hands by the side of the thighs.Gaze in front."\n" 
<b>2.</b>Bring the hands up straight towards the sky, fingers pointing upward."\n"
<b>3.</b>Raise your hands straight in front up to arms. Palms facing each other."\n"
<b>4.</b>Now slowly raise your heels and stand on toes. Raise heels as much as you can."\n"
<b>5.</b>Stretch body up as much as possible."\n" 
<b>6.</b>For returning to the original position, bring your heels on the ground first."\n"
<b>7.</b>And then slowly bring down your hands also."\n" 

"\n" <b>Fruit of Asana</b>"\n"
This Asana mproves posture,strengthens thighs,knees and ankles,"\n"
firms abdomen and buttocks,relieves sciatica,reduces flat feet."\n" 
</string>
    
 <string name="asana20">VAJRASANA</string> 
<string name="string20">"\n" <b>Introduction</b>"\n"
The name comes from the Sanskrit words vajra meaning thunderbolt or diamond"\n"
and asana meaning posture or seat."\n"
"\n"Procedure"\n"
<b>1.</b>The practitioner sits on the heels with the calves beneath the thighs."\n"
<b>2.</b>There is a four finger gap between the knee-caps,"\n" 
and the first toe of both the feet touch each other and sit erect."\n"
"\n"<b>Fruit of Asana</b>"\n"
This asana helps in digestive issues like constipation."\n"
It also strengthens the muscles of the legs and back."\n"
"\n"<b>Caution</b>"\n"
Some orthopaedic surgeons claim Vajrasana may be harmful to knees."\n"
It has also been linked to damage to the common fibular nerve resulting in foot drop,"\n"
where dorsiflexion of the foot is compromised and the foot drags during walking;"\n"
and in sensory loss to the dorsal surface of the foot and portions of the anterior, lower-lateral leg."\n"
In this context it has been called yoga foot drop."\n"</string>
 <string name="baddhapadmasana">Baddhpadmasana</string>
 <string name="chakrasana">Chakrasana</string>
 <string name="dhanurasana">Dhanurasana</string>
 <string name="garudasana">Garudasana</string>
 <string name="gomukhasana">Gomukhasana</string>
 <string name="halasana">Halasana</string>
 <string name="kukkutasana">Kukkutasana</string>
 <string name="makrasana">Makrasana</string>
 <string name="mandukasana">Mandukasana</string>
 <string name="matsyasana">Matsyasana</string>
 <string name="mayurasana">Mayurasana</string>
 <string name="paschimotthanasana">Paschimotthansana</string>
 <string name="sarvangasana">Sarvangasana</string>
 <string name="shalabhasana">Shalabhasana</string>
 <string name="shavasana">Shavasana</string>
 <string name="sirsasana">Sirsasana</string>
 <string name="tadasana">Tadasana</string>
 <string name="vajrasana">Vajrasana</string>
 
 <string name="asana21">Anulom Vilom</string>
 <string name="string21">"\n" <b>Introduction</b>"\n"
     In this pranayam the breath is regulated with the help of the nostril."\n"
      It helps encourages mind to higher levels of discrimination, concentration and thoughts."\n"
       Gives more energy and oxygen to the physical body and helps calm your nerves and improve circulation."\n" 

"\n"<b> Procedure</b>"\n"
<b>1.</b>Hold your right nasal with thumb, breathe in from left."\n" 
<b>2.</b>Now open right nasal and close left nasal with middle "\n"
and ring finger and breathe out from right nasal."\n" 
<b>3.</b>Now breathe in from right nasal. "\n"
<b>4.</b>Now close right nasal and open left and breathe out"\n"
 and in from left nasal and so on."\n"

"\n" <b>Fruit</b> "\n"
Problems of heart, high BP, heart blockage, vat-cuf-pit, arthritis, cartilage,bent ligaments,"\n"
 sinual fluid reduced, paralysis, neural related, depression, migraine pain, asthma, sinus, allergy can be cured."\n"

"\n"<b> Caution</b> "\n"
It should be done under the guidance of the expert if you are doing it for first time."\n" 
Patients of hypertension should refrain from holding the breath."\n" 
     
  </string>
 <string name="asana22">KapalBhati</string>
 <string name="string22">"\n" <b>Introduction</b>"\n"
     The word kapalbhati is made up of two words, kapal meaning skull and bhati means shining."\n"
      Due to the process, the organs under the skull mainly the brain and the"\n" 
      small brain are influenced in a good manner."\n" 
"\n"<b> Procedure:</b>"\n"
<b>1.</b>Keep breathing gradually while sitting in Padmasana ."\n" 
<b>2.</b>Inhale and start performing Kapalbhati as stated before,"\n"
<b>3.</b>Keep on doing this rotation swiftly in rhythmic manner."\n" 
<b>4.</b>Perform as many cycles as possible and then keep breathing gradually."\n"
All these processes are included under one cycle of Kapalbhati."\n" 

"\n" <b>Fruit</b>"\n"
Helps in cleansing, invigorating, warming, prevents illness and allergies."\n" 


"\n"<b> Caution</b>"\n"
The level of common person can go up to 200 repetitions."\n"
 It is not advisable to increase the number beyond that."\n"
Patients suffering from heart trouble, lung trouble should practice this under an expert guidance."\n" 
Those suffering from diseases of blood circulation should perform the process very carefully."\n" 
They should perform the process under the guidance and care of experts."\n"
 </string>
 <string name="asana23">Ardha Halasana</string>
 <string name="string23">"\n" <b>Introduction</b>"\n"
     This asana is similar to uttanapadasana."\n"
 The only difference is that in uttanapadasana the feet are taken high about 30 degree"\n"
 and in Ardha-Halasana it is about 90 degree."\n" 

"\n" <b>Procedure</b>"\n"
<b>1.</b>Lie on your back with feet together."\n"
 Keep your palms beside the thighs, facing the ground."\n" 
<b>2.</b>Now inhale and raise your right leg, as much as possible, without bending at the knees."\n"
 Remain in this posture for some time."\n" 
<b>3.</b>Then repeat the asana with the left leg."\n"
<b>4.</b>To release, exhale and bring the leg down slowly and relax."\n"

"\n"<b> Fruit</b> "\n"
<b>1.</b>This asana is an excellent exercise for the pelvic region."\n" 
<b>2.</b>Ardha-Halasana also burns excess fat in the thighs, hips and abdomen."\n"

"\n"<b> Caution</b> "\n"
Do not do this asana if you have following problems"\n"
<b>1.</b>Suffer from high blood pressure. "\n"
<b>2.</b>Have a detached retina "\n"
<b>3.</b>Feel any pressure in the head or neck"\n"
</string>
 <string name="asana24">Shashankasana</string>
 <string name="string24">"\n" <b>Introduction</b>"\n"
     Shashanka in Sanskrit means the moon, that’s why it is called moon pose also."\n" 
<b>Procedure</b>"\n"
<b>1.</b>Sit with legs folded backwards, heels apart, knees and toes together (sit in vajrasana)."\n" 
<b>2.</b>Adjust your hips between the heels (Vajrasana). Slowly raise your arms over the head."\n"
<b>3.</b>While exhaling, slowly bend forward and stretch your palms on the floor"\n" 
with abdomen pressing against the thighs."\n"
<b>4.</b>Then bring your face downwards and touch the floor with the"\n" 
forehead without raising the buttocks."\n"
 Inhaling slowly, return to an upright position, and then reverse the process."\n"
<b>5.</b>Slowly revert to the normal position of Vajrasana."\n"
 You may do this asana at least 8 to 10 times."\n"
 
 "\n" <b>Fruit</b>"\n"
This asana stretches the rectus muscle of the abdomen,"\n"
helps in improving the digestion,relieves constipation and"\n" 
benefits people with sciatica and hypertension."\n"

"\n"<b> Caution</b>"\n" 
Do not release the ankles from their position, without raising the back."\n" 
Not for the people who are suffering from pain in the hip joint."\n"
</string>
 <string name="asana25">Supta Vajrasana</string>
 <string name="string25">"\n" <b>Introduction</b>"\n"
     This asana is the further development of Vajrasana."\n"
Supta in Sanskrit means supine and Vajrasana means lying on the back."\n"
We lie on our back with folded legs, hence, it is called Supta-Vajrasana."\n" 

"\n"<b> Procedure</b>"\n"
<b>1.</b>Sit in Vajrasana."\n" 
<b>2.</b>Slowly take the help of right elbow, then left elbow and"\n" 
place them on the ground towards backside."\n" 
<b>3.</b>Slowly straighten you hands and completely lie on your back."\n"
<b>4.</b>Shoulders should rest on the ground. Beginners may keep their hands on respective thighs."\n"
 Knees should remain together."\n"
<b>5.</b>After practicing this position well, making the shape of a scissor with both hands,"\n"
bring them under the shoulders."\n"
<b>6.</b>Right hand will remain under left shoulder and left under the right,"\n"
 head in the middle of them. Stay in the position for a while and then release."\n"
<b>7.</b>While returning to the original position, first take out your hands "\n"
and place it by the side of your body."\n"
<b>8.</b>Now, with the help of elbows sit as in the first position."\n"

"\n"<b> Fruit</b>"\n"
This stretches the thigh muscles and the abdomen,stomach is stimulated,"\n" 
strengthens the thighs,helps those suffering from constipation,cures sciatica."\n"

"\n"<b> Caution</b>"\n"
There should never be more than normal pressure on the back, arms, "\n"
and the ankle joints while doing this exercise."\n"
     
</string>
 <string name="asana26">Ushtrasana</string>
 <string name="string26">"\n" <b>Introduction</b>"\n"
     The word ushtra refers to Camel. In this asana,"\n"
the body resembles the neck of a camel, that is why it is called Ushtrasana."\n" 

"\n"<b> Procedure</b>"\n"
<b>1.</b>Sit with legs stretched, heels together, palms pressing on the ground by the side of buttocks,"\n"
to keep the body at right angles to the legs with an erect spine."\n" 
<b>2.</b>Bend right leg backwards."\n" 
<b>3.</b>Bend the left leg to come to Vajrasana."\n" 
<b>4.</b>Raise up making the trunk vertical."\n" 
<b>5.</b>Inhale and bend the body backwards and bring the hands on the heels."\n"
<b>6.</b>Inhale and lift the head up, place the hands on the hips and"\n" 
tilt forward into a straight line and EXHALE. Perform once or twice."\n"

"\n"<b> Fruit</b>"\n"
This asana stretches the upper and lower thigh and knees,the focus point is the spine,"\n"
limbers the entire spine and pelvis. It will open the chest allowing for deeper breathing."\n"

"\n"<b> Caution</b>"\n"
Not for the persons who have hernia,"\n"
 recent or chronic knee, shoulder, neck or back injury or inflammation."\n"
 </string>
 
 <string name="asana28">Pavanmuktasana</string>
 <string name="string28">"\n" <b>Introduction</b>"\n"
     In Sanskrit Pavan means air, mukta means release or free."\n"
Pavanmuktasana balances the wind in whole body."\n" 

"\n" <b>Procedure</b>"\n"
<b>1.</b>Lie on your back. Hug your knees into your chest, while you keep your head,"\n"
 neck and shoulders relaxed and on the floor."\n" 
<b>2.</b>Breathe normal."\n"
<b>3.</b>Focus: Close your eyes or gaze beyond your knees and relax your back muscles."\n"
<b>4.</b>Hold the posture for as long as it feels good. Practice this posture after backbends to release the muscles."\n"
<b>5.</b>While inhaling release both the legs. "\n"
<b>6.</b>One must rest before repeating the exercise."\n"

"\n"<b> Fruit of Asana</b>"\n" 
This posture releases the muscles of the lower back and relaxes the body,"\n"
regulates wind in the body,relieves constipation and indigestion,reduces obesity"\n"
and excessive fat of the abdomen,helps in keeping away the disease of the lungs"\n"
and the heart,for people suffering from wind trouble, acidity and gas formation,"\n"
 it has an instant corrective effect."\n"

"\n"<b> Caution</b>"\n"
<b>1.</b>Pregnant women should not perform this asana."\n"
<b>2.</b>People with serious back conditions, such as sciatica and slipped disc should avoid this asana."\n"
</string>
 
 
</resources>